<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>All News | HOPO Therapeutics</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>All News</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2025 HOPO Therapeutics, Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:square]</url>
      <title>All News</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPO Therapeutics awarded BARDA contract of up to $226 million</title>
      <link>/post/2024-barda1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2024-barda1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aspr.hhs.gov/AboutASPR/ProgramOffices/BARDA/Pages/default.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority&lt;/a&gt;
 (BARDA) has awarded HOPO Therapeutics an R&amp;amp;D contract of up to $226 million to advance the company’s oral decorporation agent HOPO-101 through registrational studies. This partnership with BARDA aims to progress HOPO-101 to FDA approval as a medical countermeasure to treat exposure to radioactive actinide elements, as well as other forms of heavy metal toxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2024/10/28/2970174/0/en/HOPO-Therapeutics-Awarded-Up-to-226-Million-from-BARDA-for-Advanced-Development-of-its-Oral-Decorporation-Agent-for-Heavy-Metal-Toxicity.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read the full press release&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPO Therapeutics jointly awarded $1.78M ARPA-E Grant</title>
      <link>/post/2023-arpae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023-arpae/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Energy is funding a collaborative research effort by HOPO Therapeutics and 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.umarofoods.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Umaro Foods&lt;/a&gt;
 aimed at extracting rare earth elements and platinum group metals from seaweed. Funding for the project, totalling $1.86M, is part of a larger $5M effort 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arpa-e.energy.gov/news-and-media/press-releases/us-department-energy-announces-teams-selected-explore-critical&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;announced today&lt;/a&gt;
 by the Advaned Reserach Projects Agency-Energy (ARPA-E).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The joint research program between HOPO and Umaro, neighboring tenants at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bakarlabs.berkeley.edu/umaro-hopo-win-joint-arpa-e-funding-to-extract-rare-earth-elements-from-seaweed/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bakar Labs&lt;/a&gt;
 and also both part of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.activate.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Activate&lt;/a&gt;
 &amp;amp; Berkeley Lab&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cyclotronroad.lbl.gov&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cyclotron Road&lt;/a&gt;
, will begin in early 2024. Read more 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bakarlabs.berkeley.edu/umaro-and-hopo-bakar-labs-tenants-partner-in-doe-funded-project-to-extract-rare-earth-elements-from-seaweed/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phase 1 Clinical Trial of HOPO 14-1 Now Recruiting</title>
      <link>/post/2023-clinicaltrial2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023-clinicaltrial2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first-in-human Phase 1 clinical trial of the drug candidate HOPO 14-1 is now enrolling healthy participants. Questions about recruitment can be directed to 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:clinical-trials%40sri.com?subject=NCT05628961,%20SRI-HOPO-01,%20Study%20of%20Single%20Oral%20Doses%20of%20HOPO%2014-1%20Evaluating%20Safety,%20Tolerability,%20Pharmacokinetics&#34;&gt;clinical-trials@sri.com&lt;/a&gt;
 and full information, including eligibility requirements, can be found at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05628961&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05628961&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEO Julian Rees named 2023 Activate Fellow</title>
      <link>/post/2023-activate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023-activate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HOPO Therapeutics CEO Dr. Julian Rees has been named a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.activate.org/news/meet-cohort-2023&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2023 Activate Fellow.&lt;/a&gt;
 This prestigious 2-year fellowship for scientist-entrepreneurs is designed to support and accelerate the development of technologies with the potential to change the world, and will enable HOPO&amp;rsquo;s advancement of multiple programs in the defense, medicine, and global health spheres. As part of the fellowship, HOPO Therapeutics will join Berkeley Lab&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cyclotronroad.lbl.gov&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cyclotron Road&lt;/a&gt;
 program.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2015, Activate empowers scientists to reinvent the world by launching startups to address climate change and other global challenges. Working between government, philanthropy, universities, and the private sector, Activate transforms scientists into high-impact entrepreneurs through the Activate Fellowship, a two-year immersive experience that provides funding and fosters the resources, knowledge, networks, investors, and partnerships that fellows need to succeed. Activate is a 501(c)3 nonprofit and does not charge any fee or equity for fellows to participate. Activate’s entrepreneurial fellowship model originated from the Cyclotron Road program at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, a founding Activate partner. Activate supports fellows in communities across the U.S.: Activate Berkeley, Activate Boston, Activate New York, and Activate Anywhere, and will be launching Activate Houston in 2024. Learn more at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.activate.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Activate.org.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launch of Phase 1 Clinical Trial for HOPO 14-1</title>
      <link>/post/2023-clinicaltrial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023-clinicaltrial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HOPO Therapeutics is pleased to announce that SRI International has commenced a Phase 1 clinical trial for HOPO 14-1, with funding from the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Disease. The open label study will assess safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics, and excretion in 42 healthy participants, and is being conducted at SRI&amp;rsquo;s Plymouth, Michican facility. Coverage from 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/health-65595250&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the BBC&lt;/a&gt;
 and from 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/premium/article/new-medicine-pill-nuclear-radiation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;National Geographic&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to see the progression of our lead compound to into clinical development, passing a major milestone in our mission to develop novel and accessible treatments for life-threatening heavy metal toxicity. For more information about the trial, please visit 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05628961&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05628961&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poets &amp; Quants names HOPO Therapeutics a 2022 Most Disruptive MBA Startup</title>
      <link>/post/2022-pq/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2022-pq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HOPO Therapeutics has been named of 2022&amp;rsquo;s Most Disruptive MBA Startups by Poets &amp;amp; Quants. Hannah Weber, VP of Strategy &amp;amp; Business Development, sat down with Jeff Schmitt to discuss our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lead poisoning affects over 1 billion people, comparable to Malaria or HIV, but there has been no innovation in treatment in decades. With 99% of all patients left without any available treatment, most living in low- and middle-income countries, we feel driven to provide a safe and affordable solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can very clearly envision a world where HOPO has built a new model for access to medicines. We see ourselves as a global health company, and are aiming to create novel, affordable medicines that will finally make heavy metal exposure treatable. As metal pollution increases, we want to create a world where living in older housing, or next to an airfield, or near a recycling plant does not predetermine poor health or intelligence outcomes. Our long-term goal is for HOPO to be at the intersection of breakthrough therapies and equitable, accessible healthcare.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://poetsandquants.com/2022/12/16/2022-most-disruptive-mba-startups-hopo-therapeutics-u-c-berkeley-haas/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pqimg.png&#34; width=100%&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPO Therapeutics named as an awardee in CLS Inspire QuickFire Challenge for BIPOC Communities</title>
      <link>/post/2022-jji-qfc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2022-jji-qfc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson Innovation LLC, together with California Life Sciences (CLS) and AbbVie, has selected HOPO Therapeutics as an awardee of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jnjinnovation.com/innovation-challenges/cls-inspire-quickfire-challenge-bipoc-communities?utm_campaign=Program%20%E2%80%93%20RSE&amp;amp;utm_content=227476388&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;hss_channel=tw-20531154&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CLS Inspire QuickFire Challenge for BIPOC Communities&lt;/a&gt;
. This QuickFire Challenge recognizes innovative companies that are focusing on addressing healthcare disparities that impact historically excluded communities in the United States. As part of the award, HOPO Therapeutics receives grant funding and a year of complimentary membership to CLS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOPO’s mission is to develop treatments for heavy metal poisoning, a decades-old public health crisis that disproportionately impacts low-income communities of color around the world. We are so grateful to the teams at Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson Innovation, AbbVie, and CLS for supporting us in this mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jnjinnovation.com/innovation-challenges/cls-inspire-quickfire-challenge-bipoc-communities?utm_campaign=Program%20%E2%80%93%20RSE&amp;utm_content=227476388&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;hss_channel=tw-20531154&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;awardimg.jpeg&#34; width=95%&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berkeley Haas Features HOPO &amp; VP Hannah Weber</title>
      <link>/post/2022-haas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2022-haas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vice President of Strategy and Business Development 
&lt;a href=&#34;../../authors/hannah_weber&#34;&gt;Hannah Weber&lt;/a&gt;
 was interviewed for a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsroom.haas.berkeley.edu/startup-spotlight-hopo-therapeutics-imagines-a-future-without-heavy-metal-poisoning/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Startup Spotlight&lt;/a&gt;
 by UC Berkeley&amp;rsquo;s Haas School of Business. Hannah is completing a dual degree program at Berkeley, earning her MBA and Master&amp;rsquo;s of Public Health, and highlights both her personal goals and HOPO&amp;rsquo;s mission in global health.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://newsroom.haas.berkeley.edu/startup-spotlight-hopo-therapeutics-imagines-a-future-without-heavy-metal-poisoning/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;hmw.png&#34; width=35%&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPO Therapeutics completes California Life Sciences FAST Program</title>
      <link>/post/fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/fast/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plutonium targets immune response, lipid homeostasis, other cellular processes</title>
      <link>/post/2022-putox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2022-putox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Plutonium, the radioactive element most notable for its use in nuclear weapons, is highly toxic not just due to its radioactivity. In new research from Rebecca Abergel, Ph.D., and co-workers at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, underlying cellular response mechanisms have been uncovered that show how, as a toxic heavy metal, plutonium can damage organs in ways other than radioactive decay. This new insight can aid in the design and development of medical countermeasures to safeguard human health in the event of exposure. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2666765722000801&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read the paper&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hannah Weber joins HOPO Therapeutics as VP, Strategy &amp; Business Development</title>
      <link>/post/hannah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/hannah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HOPO Therapeutics is thrilled to welcome 
&lt;a href=&#34;../../authors/hannah_weber&#34;&gt;Hannah Weber&lt;/a&gt;
 as our new Vice President of Strategy and Business Development. Formerly a Consultant with L.E.K.&amp;lsquo;s Life Sciences practice in Boston, her industry expertise and commitment to global health make her an exceptional addition to the management team.
&lt;img src=&#34;hmw.png&#34; width=35%&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toxicity mechanisms of gadolinium uncovered</title>
      <link>/post/2022-gdtox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2022-gdtox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gadolinium, a lanthanide element used extensively in MRI contrast agents, is inherently toxic. This work identifies some of the key cellular pathways that gadolinium can interfere with, and provides some insight into the underlying causes of certain symptoms associated with exposure to gadolinium. Notably, the metal seemed to disrupt enzyme function and metal chaperone proteins involved in cellular metabolism. The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1039/D1MO00267H&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;full peer-reviewed paper&lt;/a&gt;
 was published today in the journal &lt;em&gt;Molecular Omics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New strategic direction for the company announced</title>
      <link>/post/news2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/news2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a newsletter sent last week, Julian Rees Ph.D. details a strategic shift in the company&amp;rsquo;s initial focus indication to address childhood lead poisoning, a largely unseen crisis taking place in many disadvantaged communities across the United States and abroad. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchi.mp/eb4a68f3ad09/exciting-news-from-hopo-therapeutics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read&lt;/a&gt;
 the full letter and 
&lt;a href=&#34;../../#contact&#34;&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt;
 to future updates!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPO Therapeutics joins Pad-13 program at Berkeley SkyDeck</title>
      <link>/post/skydeck/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/skydeck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to join 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://skydeck.berkeley.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Berkeley SkyDeck&lt;/a&gt;
, the University of California, Berkeley&amp;rsquo;s startup accelerator, as part of their Pad-13 program this fall! SkyDeck&amp;rsquo;s intensive mentorship and training program, as well as their vast network of contacts to industry experts, advisors, and investors, will help accelerate our growth and development over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPO Therapeutics team awarded 2021 Bakar Fellowship from UC Berkeley</title>
      <link>/post/bakar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/bakar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/bakarfellows/about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bakar Fellows Program&lt;/a&gt;
, a highly competitive faculty entrepreneurship initiative at the University of California, Berkeley, has selected the founding team of HOPO Therapeutics, Inc. for their 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/bakarfellows/2021-2022-fellows&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2021 cohort&lt;/a&gt;
. This funding will support research and development activities to further the commercialization of our lead drug compound, 3,4,3,-LI(1,2-HOPO), as well as market and patient research aimed at identifying underlying causes and risk factors for increased retention of gadolinium following MRI contrast administration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebecca Abergel granted tenure</title>
      <link>/post/tenure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/tenure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Co-founder Rebecca Abergel has been promoted to Associate Professor of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://nuc.berkeley.edu/faculty/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nuclear Engineering at the University of California, Berkeley&lt;/a&gt;
, and granted tenure. Her research program is colocated at 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://abergel.lbl.gov&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory&lt;/a&gt;
, a US Department of Energy National Laboratory, and focuses on the fundamental, biological, and applied science of heavy metals and radionuclides.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter to stakeholders from CEO Julian Rees</title>
      <link>/post/news1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/news1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Co-founder and CEO Julian Rees, Ph.D. sent a letter yesterday with important company news and updates - you can read it 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchi.mp/0c4761470ec9/ceo-letter-june-2021&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
. Join our 
&lt;a href=&#34;../../#contact&#34;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;
 to stay on top of more news!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lanthanide toxicity research highlighted by NPR&#39;s Marketplace, Berkeley Lab</title>
      <link>/post/lanthanide_toxicity2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/lanthanide_toxicity2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Co-founder Rebecca Abergel, Ph.D. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marketplace.org/2021/04/30/the-u-s-is-trying-to-reclaim-its-rare-earth-mantle/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;spoke to Marketplace&amp;rsquo;s Sabri Ben-Achour&lt;/a&gt;
 about how rare earth elements such as gadolinium are used, produced, and purified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, a Department of Energy National Lab and home to the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://abergel.lbl.gov&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BioActinide Chemistry group&lt;/a&gt;
, also 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://newscenter.lbl.gov/2021/06/07/heavy-metals-disease-yeast/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;covered this recent discovery&lt;/a&gt;
 and its applications for new discoveries in lanthanide toxicity and human health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOPO Therapeutics develops safe and orally-available chelating agents that bind to and remove heavy metals from the body. Originally 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://newscenter.lbl.gov/2019/09/12/how-an-anti-nuclear-contamination-pill-could-also-help-mri-patients/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;designed for use in a nuclear disaster scenario&lt;/a&gt;
, new applications for 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-22511-6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;exposure to gadolinium&lt;/a&gt;
, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1039/C7NJ04559J&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;lead, cadmium&lt;/a&gt;
, and a range of other heavy metals are being studied. &lt;em&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../science/&#34;&gt;Learn more about our science&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2025952118&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Original article from the &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences&lt;/em&gt; here.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New research details toxicity mechanisms of the lanthanides</title>
      <link>/post/lanthanide_toxicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/lanthanide_toxicity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The elements of lanthanide series, which are rare earth heavy metals, are increasingly utilized in a range of industries, including consumer electronics, emerging energy technologies, and medicine. While elements such as gadolinium and lanthanum are routinely administered to patients in pharmaceutical products, little is known about their toxicological profile. As human exposure to these elements through both intentional and accidental means continues to rise, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2025952118&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;studies such as this&lt;/a&gt;
 are essential to understanding, preventing, and treating the negative health outcomes associated with these toxic heavy metals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOPO Therapeutics develops safe and orally-available chelating agents that bind to and remove heavy metals from the body. Originally 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://newscenter.lbl.gov/2019/09/12/how-an-anti-nuclear-contamination-pill-could-also-help-mri-patients/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;designed for use in a nuclear disaster scenario&lt;/a&gt;
, new applications for 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-22511-6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;exposure to gadolinium&lt;/a&gt;
, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1039/C7NJ04559J&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;lead, cadmium&lt;/a&gt;
, and a range of other heavy metals are being studied. &lt;em&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../science/&#34;&gt;Learn more about our science&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2025952118&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Original article from the &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences&lt;/em&gt; here.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPO-Einsteinium complex published in Nature</title>
      <link>/post/nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/nature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Designed to selectively chelate the rare earth f-block elements, 3,4,3-LI(1,2-HOPO) - the active ingredient in HOPO Therapeutics&amp;rsquo; lead drug candidate - has allowed researchers in Rebecca Abergel&amp;rsquo;s group at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory to provide the first measurements of an einsteinium bond length. It also reinforces the unmatched capability of this chelator to bind f-block metal ions such as gadolinium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally published in the journal 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-03179-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
, additional reporting is available from 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://newscenter.lbl.gov/2021/02/03/discoveries-at-the-edge-of-the-periodic-table-first-ever-measurements-of-einsteinium/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Berkeley Lab&lt;/a&gt;
, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nbcnews.com/science/science-news/mysterious-radioactive-element-einsteinium-measured-first-time-n1256870&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NBC News&lt;/a&gt;
, and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/07/science/einsteinium-chemistry-elements.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../science/&#34;&gt;Learn more about our science&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPO&#39;s chelator featured in Cancer Cytopathology</title>
      <link>/post/acs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/acs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The development of HOPO Therapeutics&amp;rsquo; lead drug candidate as a medical countermeasure for use in a radiological disaster scenario is detailed in an interview with co-founder 
&lt;a href=&#34;../../authors/rebecca_abergel/&#34;&gt;Rebecca Abergel, Ph.D.&lt;/a&gt;
 in &lt;em&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/cncy.22298&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cancer Cytopathology&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;, a journal of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cancer.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;American Cancer Society&lt;/a&gt;
. An effective treatment for removal of radioactive and other heavy metals from the body, its performance in preclinical trials has been vastly superior to any other chelating agent.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;../../science/&#34;&gt;Learn more about our science&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prior Press Coverage of HOPO&#39;s Foundational Work</title>
      <link>/post/priorpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/priorpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.berkeley.edu/story_jump/five-berkeley-faculty-members-elected-fellows-of-the-aaas/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Rebecca Abergel elected a fellow of the American Association for the Advancement of Science (UC Berkeley)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dailycal.org/2019/09/15/berkeley-lab-creates-anti-nuclear-contamination-pill-to-help-mri-patients/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Berkeley Lab creates anti-nuclear contamination pill to help MRI patients (The Daily Californian)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://newscenter.lbl.gov/2019/09/12/how-an-anti-nuclear-contamination-pill-could-also-help-mri-patients/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;A Single Dose for Good Measure: How an Anti-Nuclear-Contamination Pill Could Also Help MRI Patients (Berkeley Lab News)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-018-22511-6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Julian Rees and Rebecca Abergel Publish Proof-of-Concept Study Showing Effective Treatment for Gadolinium Contamination&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.innovatorsunder35.com/the-list/rebecca-abergel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Rebecca Abergel named to MIT Technology Review&amp;rsquo;s list of Innovators Under 35&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://newscenter.lbl.gov/2012/03/06/responding-to-the-radiation-threat/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Responding to the Radiation Threat (Berkeley Lab News)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPO Therapeutics, Inc. is established</title>
      <link>/post/incorporation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/incorporation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOPO Therapeutics, Inc. announces incorporation and the appointments of Rebecca J. Abergel, Ph.D., and Julian A. Rees, Ph.D. to the Board of Directors.  Julian A. Rees is also named President and Chief Executive Officer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;../../authors/rebecca_abergel&#34;&gt;Dr. Abergel&lt;/a&gt;
, Assistant Professor in the Department of Nuclear Engineering at the University of California, Berkeley, and Faculty Scientist in the Chemical Sciences Division at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, is a world-renowned expert in the biological chemistry of the actinide elements.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;../../authors/julian_rees&#34;&gt;Dr. Rees&lt;/a&gt;
 joins HOPO Therapeutics as President and Chief Executive Office after a postdoctoral fellowship at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory. His research included proof-of-concept and validation studies of HOPO&amp;rsquo;s lead drug candidate for indications related to gadolinium deposition.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
