<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Company | HOPO Therapeutics</title>
    <link>/tags/company/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/company/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Company</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 HOPO Therapeutics, Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:square]</url>
      <title>Company</title>
      <link>/tags/company/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>New strategic direction for the company announced</title>
      <link>/post/news2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/news2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a newsletter sent last week, Julian Rees Ph.D. details a strategic shift in the company&amp;rsquo;s initial focus indication to address childhood lead poisoning, a largely unseen crisis taking place in many disadvantaged communities across the United States and abroad. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchi.mp/eb4a68f3ad09/exciting-news-from-hopo-therapeutics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read&lt;/a&gt; the full letter and 
&lt;a href=&#34;../../#contact&#34;&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt; to future updates!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPO Therapeutics joins Pad-13 program at Berkeley SkyDeck</title>
      <link>/post/skydeck/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/skydeck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to join 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://skydeck.berkeley.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Berkeley SkyDeck&lt;/a&gt;, the University of California, Berkeley&amp;rsquo;s startup accelerator, as part of their Pad-13 program this fall! SkyDeck&amp;rsquo;s intensive mentorship and training program, as well as their vast network of contacts to industry experts, advisors, and investors, will help accelerate our growth and development over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPO Therapeutics team awarded 2021 Bakar Fellowship from UC Berkeley</title>
      <link>/post/bakar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/bakar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/bakarfellows/about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bakar Fellows Program&lt;/a&gt;, a highly competitive faculty entrepreneurship initiative at the University of California, Berkeley, has selected the founding team of HOPO Therapeutics, Inc. for their 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/bakarfellows/2021-2022-fellows&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;2021 cohort&lt;/a&gt;. This funding will support research and development activities to further the commercialization of our lead drug compound, 3,4,3,-LI(1,2-HOPO), as well as market and patient research aimed at identifying underlying causes and risk factors for increased retention of gadolinium following MRI contrast administration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebecca Abergel granted tenure</title>
      <link>/post/tenure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/tenure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Co-founder Rebecca Abergel has been promoted to Associate Professor of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://nuc.berkeley.edu/faculty/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nuclear Engineering at the University of California, Berkeley&lt;/a&gt;, and granted tenure. Her research program is colocated at 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://abergel.lbl.gov&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory&lt;/a&gt;, a US Department of Energy National Laboratory, and focuses on the fundamental, biological, and applied science of heavy metals and radionuclides.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter to stakeholders from CEO Julian Rees</title>
      <link>/post/news1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/news1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Co-founder and CEO Julian Rees, Ph.D. sent a letter yesterday with important company news and updates - you can read it 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchi.mp/0c4761470ec9/ceo-letter-june-2021&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Join our 
&lt;a href=&#34;../../#contact&#34;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; to stay on top of more news!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOPO Therapeutics, Inc. is established</title>
      <link>/post/incorporation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/incorporation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOPO Therapeutics, Inc. announces incorporation and the appointments of Rebecca J. Abergel, Ph.D., and Julian A. Rees, Ph.D. to the Board of Directors.  Julian A. Rees is also named President and Chief Executive Officer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;../../authors/rebecca_abergel&#34;&gt;Dr. Abergel&lt;/a&gt;, Assistant Professor in the Department of Nuclear Engineering at the University of California, Berkeley, and Faculty Scientist in the Chemical Sciences Division at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, is a world-renowned expert in the biological chemistry of the actinide elements.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;../../authors/julian_rees&#34;&gt;Dr. Rees&lt;/a&gt; joins HOPO Therapeutics as President and Chief Executive Office after a postdoctoral fellowship at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory. His research included proof-of-concept and validation studies of HOPO&amp;rsquo;s lead drug candidate for indications related to gadolinium deposition.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
